This is going to be your most important meaty as a Cammy player after grab
'cause you're gonna see yourself landing a lot of grabs in the corner.
You gonna need to know this meaty extremely well
and you have to time it though.
It is not auto-timed, this is a manually timed meaty
so you actually have to just do it yourself and get the rhythm and timing down.
Yo, yo, yo.
What is good, YouTube?
It's your boy, Punk, and we are back with another video.
And today we have a really good video
I would say.
This is the first time we've ever gonna be doing this on the channel.
And, you know, hopefully we are going to be doing it a lot more with this game.
And that is going to be our first ever Street Fighter 6 guide
and of course, it's gonna be for our girl
Cammy, since, you know, I've been playing Cammy quite a lot in this game
probably the most character.
..
Well, not probably, it's definitely the most character I've played since the release of Street Fighter 6 and we're pretty much going to be making a god with her today.
We're gonna be going over everything from combos to her
her buttons and strategies I use when I play.
Everything that you got to become the best Cammy player and surpass Master Punk.
You know what I'm saying?
So if you looking forward to playing some Cammy
you trying to learn her, this is the place to be right now.
So yeah, without further ado, I need you to go like
comment, subscribe, and turn the post notification bell on
and let's get into it.
So first thing you wanna do is go over all of Cammy's frame data and jabs
her normals, and for her frame datas and the normals.
So first you have her stand jab and her crouch jab
which is pretty much gonna be the same button I would say.
Stand jab and crouch jab you pretty much would think of as the same.
I think, uh, crouch jab would probably be your better button to use for getting out of situations.
And I don't really know, stand jab is just kind of used in block strings for the most part
they are four frames, so this is your fastest button with Cammy.
These, or both of them actually.
I don't think there's many characters in this game that has two four-frame buttons
but Cammy has two four-frame jabs, so these are your fastest buttons that you want to use.
And then you have her light kick
which this button is very good, and you can use for a lot of different things.
You can obviously use it for, you know
you could do block strings, like things like that.
You can get four if you close enough.
Okay.
Yeah, so you can get four of those.
On hit, you can actually just get the four
the combo, like that, but.
..
Bro, why is it not comboing?
It maybe is jammy hurt by it for may- oh
it might only work on crouching is what it is.
Okay, so yeah, there you go.
And on block you can do it crouching also.
But yeah, if they're crouching you can actually get this block string to
oh, three jabs into a light kick
which is very good.
I don't actually think there's any other character in the game they even have that
to my knowledge.
And on hit you can see, you get the combo when they're crouching.
Which is that combo.
And if they're standing you don't really get it
but you can still do jab, jab
light kick.
So still pretty much the same concept.
Next button we gonna be getting into is
which is one of my favorite buttons which Cammy I like to use
is her standard medium kick.
This button is amazing, as you can see the range
you just see where it hitting jammy from
all the way back here.
This button is amazing, not only the fact that it hits from so far
but even on block, look how much drive gauge you take
which is very important in this game.
You want to always look at how much meter drive gauge is losing when you press a button.
And Cammy medium kick take about a half a bar I would say
so this button is really good to abuse your opponent's drive gauge with
not only on, to hit them, but even just on block is very good.
And it's only minus four so you never really have to worry about getting punished.
You should never be in range, if you do it from here.
Oh, look, it even spaces itself out
so even if you did it from this close
you're still not going to get punished, ever.
So this is pretty much gonna be one of your best pokes with Cammy that you wanna use when you're playing footsies
okay?
So that is very important.
Next one we're gonna go over is the standard medium punch.
Pretty good button, not really used how you would use it in older Street Fighter games
which is for pressure, but this time it is used pretty much I would say to frame trap with
and also it is very good I found out in meaties with Cammy.
So if you do a meaty, I wouldn't say just do this button on block
but you can definitely just throw it out sometimes and you can get a combo if it does randomly get a counter.
So let's say you're playing and you just see a counter hit
you can do a combo with it, you can get standard medium punch and clear
so it is very good if you see it counter hit and if you get
going for a frame trap, which we'll get into later on in the guide.
So, but the best way I've found out using this button is in meaties after
like, grabs.
So you grab someone in the corner, you could do something like that.
Right?
So we're gonna get into those things later though
so for now, this button, you know
I don't really know what to tell you.
You wouldn't really use it too much, since it's not really cancelable.
It's really used in pressure for the most part
not really in neutral.
You wouldn't really press this button in neutral at all.
So yeah, we're gonna come back to this one a bit later on in the video when we get into
like, setups and those kind of things.
Next button we are going to go over is the.
..
Crouching medium kick, which this one is an important button.
This is one of my favorite buttons also
just like the standard medium kick.
I love the crouch medium kick and that is because the crouching medium kick is gonna be one of your main whiff punish buttons
and also it's just a really good low range poke
so since we have the mechanic drive rush
right?
If you think that your opponent will not block his feet
and you wanna go for some.
..
Or even if you wanna just start some pressure up and you have a lot of drive gauge
you can always just go straight into the crouching medium kick drive rush.
If they hit you, you get big combos.
If not, you can get good pressure on block with this
to do things like that and you remember that in drive rush
all your buttons are a plus, so get a lot of good pressure starting out from this crouching medium kick.
But for the whiff punish part, this is gonna be one of your main whiff punish buttons for the simple fact you.
..
It's your longest ranging cancellable poke into drive rush and also into special moves
right?
So you could do low forward spiral arrow
maybe low forward DP if you feeling it.
I suck, but yeah, you could do low forward DP which is.
..
We're gonna show you here.
Look at that.
You see how far I hit that from?
Look it.
Man.
Get your, get your power ball.
Get all this pressure starting, which is very good
and that's pretty much gonna be how you wanna use your crouching medium kick.
Crouching medium punch, I would say this button is a bit similar to a standard medium punch
but it is cancellable, so I would say it does have a bit more use in neutral.
Which is, you can buffer this button as you see
if you looking at my inputs on the screen
you see me buffering into drill right here
and it's never coming out.
But let's say that Jamie, or not Jamie
but your opponent, you know, they're walking blocking.
Uh, hold on.
Let me record there.
Walking blocking, let's say your opponent, you know
they're doing it.
And you just casually pressing this, obviously
uh, in a real match, it'll probably be more effective to buffer it like that.
You see as he walked into range?
It's a very good button to just buffer while your opponent may be just walking in and out of the ranges
or you can even buffer it to drive rush if you wanna be a little bit more safe.
But this button is gonna be a bit harder to whiff punish in neutral
so you have more freedom to just press it and not worry about being whiff punished.
But unlike low- crouch and medium kick, you don't wanna just press this button on whiff because it is very easy to whiff punish I would say.
So you don't wanna just be whiffing this button a lot.
But this?
I would say you have more freedom to just whiff and buffer into your low spiral arrow
or even to super if you want to
or to drive rush of course, and you get a big combos.
So, I would say that is the best use for the crouch medium punch.
And now we're moving on to actually my very favorite button with Cammy
which is going to be the standing heavy kick.
This button here has so many great uses in the neutral that is.
..
Well, it's only really a neutral button because you can't cancel it or anything.
But one, my favorite is for them to block the standing heavy kick because if you look at this
boom, look at the bar.
You see the drive gauge is also minus four
just like your stand medium kick, so the drive gauge is going down.
Crazy.
So this is a very good drive gauge abuse button
you know what I'm saying?
If you wanna abuse some drive gauge, you wanna use the standing heavy kick.
And not only for it on block.
Stand heavy kick is also a really good whiff punish button because this button has a bit more range than the standing medium kick
right?
So sometimes you're not in range to whiff punish or
you know, in range for the standard medium kick
but.
..
Or not the stand medium kick whiff punish
I mean the crouching medium kick whiff punish.
Sometimes you're not in range, like right here
but you see heavy kick hits it, and not only is it good because it hits it
it takes a whole drive gauge bar away on whiff punish.
So if you whiff punish someone with this stand heavy kick
that is a one drive gauge bar gone.
Look at it.
A whole bar just depleted because they decided to whiff a button.
And you can get some type of pressure from this
which will be like.
..
You could get something like that or you could just dash and then do it.
But yeah, this button is amazing because it does reach at ranges that your crouching medium kick
it won't whiff punish, but this will
a whole drive gauge bar.
So that is why this is one of my very favorite buttons.
And next we're going to get into her standing heavy punch.
This button is pretty good I would say.
I like it the most when I have someone cornered is when I like to use it the most because they don't have anywhere to walk out of the range to make it whiff.
Since it doesn't have that much range, it's very easy to make whiffen- whiff punish by when they're in the corner
you just can swing that thing.
It takes about a quarter of a drive gauge on block and the best thing about it is
this is probably the only button that Cammy actually can hit confirm.
So you can actually confirm this on hit to the spiral arrow to continue pressure and get a good amount of damage.
Or you could confirm.
..
It's very hard to do it, but you can confirm into the drive rush
but it is very hard.
I'm not even very consistent with that one
but confirming it into the special move is very good and I think that is the best use for this button.
You can use it in the mid-range, of course
for the same thing.
But it is, like I said, a lot easier to make whiff than a lot of the other buttons that you see.
You could be around right here and still was whiffing.
So, yeah, that is probably gonna be a use for that.
And the next button we're gonna go over is Cammy's sweep.
The crouching heavy kick is very fast, nine-frame button that is very fast for the sweep.
And it's a s- bit faster than her standing heavy kick
and about the same as her crouching medium kick.
But as you can see, this button
Cammy actually moves forward when she does the sweep
which is a very good way to whiff punish.
Whiff, which I like to use it the most for
is to whiff punish, which is boom.
You see that?
Boom, and you actually get a setup.
Let's say you could get a setup into
like, dog kick or jump in light kick.
And if you know your opponent might try to parry that
you could even go for the L key jump throw there.
But we'll get into that stuff later.
But, yeah, this is a very good whiff punish.
It also takes a whole drive gauge away on block if you whiff punish someone with it.
It is a hard knockdown, meaning they cannot tech backwards or get up in place.
They just always gonna get up right where they get knocked down at
so you get a very good setup from the jumping or jump dog kick right there.
And the dog kick also hits meaty here.
So, as you can see, it is plus one
which is very good setup to continue some pressure with after a good whiff punish.
And the last button we are going to go o-.
..
Actually, there's two more buttons.
We have the forward heavy kick.
Forward heavy kick is a button that I don't ever really use
and I think it's not the best.
It has a decent range.
You can hit confirm it one hit.
So, if it does hit you, click confirm it.
See, I don't even know.
..
Maybe it doesn't punish counter.
It might not even combo from far.
Yeah, it doesn't.
So, I don't really know, honestly.
I think that this button, as a Cammy player
you just don't really use it.
Like, you don't really wanna use this button at all.
I don't really see a use for it right now
so I would say just dead that.
Next button we are gonna go over, which I also forgot about
is the back heavy kick.
This button is pretty much gonna be used as a combo in just combos
like, do stuff like this, you know?
But we're gonna go over all the combos later
so don't even think about this button.
This is not used in the neutral or anything at all.
Maybe you could use it to anti-air with.
I think it's a pretty decent-ish anti-air.
I think it's a pretty decent anti-air, but you do have to wait a bit to do it.
You can't just do it when they jump
like, or that will happen.
You have to wait a bit.
And you could get some pretty cool combos.
I don't recommend trying it too often.
It's very inconsistent for me.
But it can be good if you somehow master it.
You could be doing big damage off of the anti-air.
Got a whole lot of options you can explore
you know?
So, yeah, I would say, if you want
you can try to anti-air with this button.
I would not recommend it, but it is possible if you get that timing down really well.
Next button we are going to go over will be her back medium punch
which is also, I would say, a pretty decent anti-air.
But it's a bit hard to use in this game.
A lot better in Street Fighter V, but still pretty good
I would say.
You don't.
..
Ooh, you can actually get the side switch mix-up like Street Fighter V.
Hmm, low-key, I might try to start using this a bit more.
I don't actually use this, ever, 'cause you can probably get the side switch mix-up into.
..
Uh.
Yeah.
And sometimes it'll stay on the.
..
Ah.
So, maybe I'll start using that a bit more.
I usually just do DP, of course
as the anti-air.
But back medium punch, you pretty much use this as an anti-air
and you would use it in combos like that
of course.
You can do that.
Things like that, but we'll go over that later.
So, this is pretty much just an anti-air if you wanna use it in neutral.
You don't really, you know, throw this button out at all.
So, this would just be an anti-air.
Pretty fast five-frame button.
The last button we are gonna go over is her crouching fierce.
This button is pretty much gives you the good combos
and it's also her only plus frame button.
If you know anything about the game right now
you know every character pretty much has one plus frame button
besides maybe two or three characters in the game.
And Cammy's is her crouching heavy punch.
So, a lot of times you wanna start pressure with this after a knockdown.
It is plus one, so if someone do try to mash their fastest button
which is Jamie's, what?
Crouching jab, I think.
Boom.
And as you can see, it counter hits.
Obviously, you cannot do, like, fierce into fierce or fierce into medium punch.
So, yeah, this is pretty much gonna be your go-to frame trap if you see people mashing.
But then if.
..
Once you s- got them stopped to mashing
of course you could do things like crouch fierce
walk up throw, crouch fierce, crouch fierce.
You can start doing crouch fierce jab.
You know, all type of frame traps start opening up once your opponents start respecting that you will do the stand jab counter hit combo right there.
So, yeah, that is gonna pretty much be your go-to button to get your frame traps off.
So, the next thing we want to go over is her special move.
She does have quite a few special moves and different versions.
And the first one we're gonna go over is going to be
of course, her classic Spiral Arrow, which in this game
actually has more uses than just combos, I would say.
One really good use is, look at this
you see it's only minus one.
You can space it out pretty well.
You can even space out the heavy version to be minus one also.
Medium version, uh, made at minus one.
You can make it minus one, minus two
it's all very good.
And it could catch your opponent off-guard walking forward since it is a fast moving move.
So you can actually just get your opponent
catch them walking forward and it's also pretty spaced out so you're not close enough to get grabbed.
So you have some freedom to just kinda block for a while
walk back, or maybe even contest with a button if you think that your opponent's gonna try to go for a big frame trap on you.
So this is, uh, a very good use for Spiral Arrow.
And of course, the one always good use is gonna be as a combo ender.
You know, you wanna end combos with the Spiral Arrow
that's what Cammy's been doing forever at this point.
So yeah, you already know, the Spiral Arrow pretty much good combo ender.
It always gives you good pressure after.
Next, we're gonna go over is her Cannon Fight
which you already know is Cammy's DP.
Also, her pretty much best anti-air.
You guarantee, 100% of the time if you do this correctly
it will anti-air your opponent out of the sky and they gonna have to respect you
you know what I'm saying?
So, definitely something that's always good to learn how to do is DP anti-air.
And also, it's gonna be, of course
just like the Spiral Arrow in the corner
this is gonna be your go-to probably ender for a lot of combos because you're at least very close and it does more damage than the Spiral Arrow.
So you pretty much start ending your combos in this.
It's just mid-screen you don't because Spiral Arrow gives a bit better pressure and you don't sacrifice a lot of
a lot of damage.
But we'll go over of course all them combos and that stuff later.
But yeah, they pretty much gonna be your go-to
your DP.
Got the charged version is heavy.
Yeah, I forgot about that.
In this game, Cammy has charged versions of the special moves where you do the heavy version.
You can charge it up for big combos and enders.
But of course, we'll go over that later.
These are all pretty much just for combos
so.
..
The next special move we're gonna go over
which we had.
..
Let's change the character.
Oh, it's gonna be our Spin Knuckle
which Spin Knuckle has a pretty.
..
a lot of good uses for it.
One of the main ones in this game
they sped it up so it's very fast and it goes through projectiles
which is why we have Ryu on the screen.
And we're going to just shoot a Hadouken.
You know, all you people out there who hate Hadouken spammers
you might consider wanting to play some Cammy because boom
look at that.
You can do it on reaction pretty well to all Hadoukens.
The only fireball I would say that is pretty hard to react to right now is Guile's Sonic Boom.
You can still do it, but it's very hard
so.
But, and of course, since it's a punish counter
you get a lot of big combos off of this
which we will go over later of course
but this is gonna be the main use for this
it's going to be to get over those projectiles.
And let's say you, you're fighting Guile and you don't get over the projectile
right?
Let's say you're fighting Guile, right?
And you wanna go over the fireball, maybe you're a bit too late.
It's pretty hard, he blocks it.
Look at that.
You go over it, you're plus three.
It is plus three on block, the heavy Spin Knuckle plus three.
I only really recommend using the heavy, I don't use other Spin Knuckles.
In neutral, pretty much just the heavy one
plus three on block.
So Guile cannot contest you in this situation at all.
If he tries to drive impact, you can drive impact back every time.
He cannot jab in this situation because he is still in a bit of recovery from Sonic Boom.
So, even if he tries to jab
which we could even set up, it will not work.
Yup, see?
That is a counter hit because he is mashing the jab.
And even if you're a bit late, you can get a trade here and get a trade combo
but every time you can always get that.
Maybe a guy will go for a perfect parry
but it is not gonna be a very easy button to perfect parry.
And also, when they are in burnout
it is very good, but I'll go over burnout stuff a bit later on in the video.
That'll be with the frame traps and all that.
Now we go over to the next special move
which is gonna be her Hooligan, which is a move a lot of people asking me about and why I don't use.
I do not right now have any uses for this move.
I've not found a good way to use it without it being very risky.
You can, of course, use it to fake out anti-airs with
you know, this version.
You can charge it up, you get a lot of good plus frames and combos.
But for me personally, it is very easy to hit out the air and they have a new juggle system in this game where if you get hit out of a special move in the air
you will take a lot of combo damage if your opponent has the big combo.
So, in high level, you get anti-aired here
they're gonna do a full combo that might take about 30
40% into more pressure.
So in my opinion, I'm not a very good
very big fan of the Hooligan yet.
Maybe some people will figure out uses on it
but for us in this video right now
we don't have a use for it.
And I don't think it is a very big thing that you need right now with Cammy.
So, I do think it's okay that even if we don't go over it right now
we don't have any use.
I don't think it's extremely necessary that she has to use it.
Am I missing any special move?
Oh, divekick.
Cammy's biggest, most hated special move if you're a competitor is going to be her divekick
which is always a very good tool for pressure.
You space it out really well, you can make it plus one block as you see
plus two, make it zero one block and even if you mess it up a bit right there
that is minus five.
You don't wanna do it in those ranges
like, here is bad.
You always wanna get it a little bit to where it's touching the toes.
You wanna get it to this.
..
You know what I'm saying?
Low, the lower that the divekick make them block
the better.
That's the rule here with divekick.
The lower they block, the better.
It's plus on blocking.
Even if you do it at these ranges
on hit you get big combos like crouch strong.
If you land it a little closer, you can always get the jabs
of course.
Those are always trustworthy.
If you land it and you're not sure.
But you do wanna make sure you practice your divekicks with Cammy.
It's gonna be a big way to start pressure and it's very hard to react to in anti-air
so people tend to block it a lot more when they do anti-air it.
Just don't get too predictable with it, of course
and just start spamming it eight times, ten times in a row.
Sometimes you might see me do that, but it's because I have a very big read that my opponent is just very scared and they're not gonna do anything.
But, you know, if you don't have that read
don't try to do that kinda stuff.
You know what I'm saying?
But yeah, that's pretty much going to be all of the special moves from Cammy.
Next, we'll go over her supers which you have her level one is going to be this
which is pretty much gonna be a combo ender for big damage and
also, if you're very close to burnout
you can end combos with this to get that last bit of bar down and burn them out.
It does not go through projectiles or anything
so you are really pretty much be using this as a main combo ender to close out a round or to burn your opponent out.
Or even sometimes I like to use it if my opponent has about
let's say, even if they have, like
about one, one bar.
It doesn't do a full bar, but it puts 'em pretty close to burnout
so next situation I could probably make them burnout on block with some pressure
so I do think that is pretty good.
I mean, overdrive specials from Cammy aren't really that good
honestly.
Her EX special moves aren't very good, I would say.
All her EX special moves are just where you can charge 'em up.
They pretty much just combo enders, just like the charged version.
They're just the charged version, just combo enders.
But yeah, that's gonna be the first super.
Pretty much just a combo ender or the burnout situation
like I stated.
And next one is gonna be her level two super
which this super has a pretty decent amount of use.
Can even go through fireballs sometimes.
Pretty hard, probably would never get through a Sonic Boom
but we can see.
When you're close enough, you have to do it from pretty close range.
Charge acquired.
Oh, look.
See, it actually punishes her.
Charge acquired.
But you cannot do it from, like
back here, let's say.
Boom, you're gonna get smacked, so you gotta be kinda in her face.
Charge acquired.
And you can get a punish on the Sonic Boom.
Also, it is very good for combo enders when you're gonna kill them and
of course, if you can put them in burnout.
This level twos take about, uh, one and.
..
A little bit like one and one-tenth of a drive gauge bar
so if they have one bar, this is guaranteed to burn them out every single time.
And even it has more use, because if you do a air combo
you can.
..
If you hit someone in the air, you can actually combo into this and it has a different property where you can get a combo ender like the DP
but we'll go over the combo enders later for this super.
Charge acquired.
But yeah, you can do it in the sky and then you can just do it raw in the air too.
Let's say you saw a S- a Sonic Boom or something and you wanna come down faster
you could do that.
But yeah, that's gonna be pretty much the uses for that.
And now we have the level three super
which is my favorite if you know, if you've been watching me
I love this super.
We call it the missile over here, 'cause you listen to it.
..
Bing!
You hear this is a missile.
And just like a missile, it travels very fast and goes across the entire screen
making it so that when your opponent has a fireball
they cannot shoot it because pretty much at every range except all the way back here.
..
Charge acquired.
Oh, what?
Bro, I've been hit out of this from fullscreen.
Charge acquired.
All right, here it go.
Oh, so maybe if you let the Sonic Boom travel a little bit
you could still.
..
It'll still actually punish, so you could do it from fullscreen.
But this is used pretty much, of course
to put your opponent in burnout, like I said before.
A level three does take about a bar and a half.
We're gonna look here.
And if you have CA, it takes two full bars
I know that.
So, takes about a bar and a half
and if it's the CA version, the CA version does about
uh, two bars, I believe.
Yep, two bars.
All CAs in this game, I think
does the same, so two bars for that
and of course, you can do this to end your combos with.
If you're throwin' a kill, it's always good to use the kill as an ender combo to close out rounds and games
of course.
But my main way I use it a lot to go through projectiles or to put my opponent in burnout because
you know, it's just so fast.
It's a missile!
It's a missile, bro!
But that is gonna be the main use of all of Cammy's supers right there.
Pretty much identical to each other, besides the level three is very good to get through fireballs.
So, the next thing we are going to go over is Cammy's drive gauge usage.
Feel like it is very important for each character to understand how to use the drive gauge
which is pretty much gonna be the same for buttons.
You can test them all out, but I'm just go over the gist of it 'cause i- if we do the whole thing
it's just gonna be like I'm going through all the last button again.
So, pretty much all your drive rush buttons you want to use
which keep this in mind, Cammy's drive rush is not the best in the game.
It does not have a lot of range
so you cannot just bust it out.
But if you go into pressure from it
you gotta remember the best buttons that you want to try to use is your standard medium punch
which is gonna give you a plus three on block
your crouching heavy punch, which is gonna give you a plus five on block
and your standing jabs, which is gonna be plus two on block.
And the reason that you wanna do these buttons out of it if your opponent is blocking is because these leave you.
..
This right here, medium punch, leaves you in range to grab them.
You don't have to walk or anything.
Also, jab does the exact same thing.
So, those two buttons you do because they leave you right in range to grab.
You don't have to walk, you can just press the grab button.
And the crouching fierce is good because it is the most plus one on block
which is plus five.
And you can also just grab straight away from it s- at some ranges.
But you can just take the slight step forward and grab.
But this is good because you can get a lot of big frame traps from it.
Crouch fierce into crouch fierce becomes a real frame trap.
If they mash, they will take very big damage.
So, that is pretty much how you would use the drive gauge with Cammy
I would say.
You don't really do things like, you know
drive rush, stand heavy kick because it's no real use for it.
You wanna use your drive rush to get plus range or to do pretty damaging combos
right?
You can also use crouching medium punch, but does not leave you in range so I wouldn't really recommend it too much.
So yeah, that's pretty much what I would say the drive.
..
You wanna pretty much use her drive system for.
You cannot really spam it too much in neutral since it's not very fast and it doesn't have a lot of range
but you can definitely catch people off guard.
I would be sometimes, you know, I won't do it at whole set
then I'll just bust it out for some quick plus range if I'm feeling it and I'm just feeling like they maybe not gonna check me in that moment.
And you can just start some pressure.
Next thing we want to go over is combos for Cammy.
Really gonna be your basic go-to combos if you do land a hit.
So, n- number one, the combo you want to have
of course, crouch and fierce into crouch medium punch.
Any time your crouch fierce hit, if it's non-counter hit
this is your best go-to combo.
Or if you may be a bit too far
you can definitely try to go for the stand and light kick
which won't really connect a lot either from far range.
So, this is pretty much your go-to combo.
If you see this crouch fierce land, it's gonna be the crouch medium punch.
Unless you do wanna go into the, you know
drive rush, but we'll talk about the drive rush after.
So, that's gonna be your basic crouch fierce combo with Cammy.
And then after, you have jab, jab
jab, of course, boom, jab, jab
jab, spiral, which you are gonna see yourself doing a lot with Cammy.
Since jabs are very good for pressure in this game
you're gonna see yourself using jabs a lot and you're gonna also see yourself landing a lot of jabs
so you're gonna need to have this combo down 100%.
Also, you could do jab, jab, light kick
which is also pretty much the same thing.
And if they are crouching, you can do jab
jab, jab, light kick.
So, these are important combos you're gonna see yourself using a lot.
If you watch any of my videos actually playing Cammy
you will see that I end up doing jab
jab combos probably more than anything else in this game right now.
Your next combo is going to be standin' medium punch.
If you see this stand medium punch land
you can always do stand light kick into spiral arrow if you are in range
of course.
Every time, this is gonna work.
This is your combo if you see this land.
Now, if you're very close and you land this
you can go into back medium punch target combo
which is gonna be a very important combo.
Pretty much anytime you clash with drive impacts with someone
which we'll go over all that stuff still
of course.
But yeah, that's gonna be a very good combo for this if you see it land up close.
Also, another good combo is gonna be crouch jab into target combo.
Always a very, very good combo with Cammy.
So, I'm gonna say that's pretty much going to be all your basic combos that you confirm into when you see stuff hit
non-counter hit, of course.
Next combo we'll go into is some counter hit combos
so.
..
Let's say you see yourself, you- you land some counter hits
you know, you start your pressure and you start frame trapping
fellas.
You land a counter hit, stand in a medium punch
you can go into a lot of different thing.
The one- best one, which is gonna be if you hit it at a further range
is going to be the crouching medium kick.
You will be able to land this on counter hit every time from pretty much any range that you see this hit.
I think this will always work.
And if you do land this a bit closer
you can get even damaging- more damaging combo which is stand medium punch into standing fierce
which is gonna do a lot of damage every time.
So this is pretty much gonna be your combo anytime you see yourself landing a counter hit with stand and medium punch
you will go into that and if you land it from further
go into the crouching medium kick.
You can also go into crouch medium punch.
Don't really see a reason to do that
unless you're.
..
You know, you pretty much gonna do either this
most of the time stand medium punch and to stand fierce or you're gonna be doing stand fierce into low forward.
There's really no reason to go for that one there.
So yeah, that is gonna be your go-to combos if you see yourself counter hit with stand medium punch.
Now if you see yourself get a counter hit with crouch and medium punch
your best combo is always gonna be crouch and medium punch two times into the spiral arrow
of course, or a special move of your choice.
Now this is one of the good ones I would say
is if you get a counter hit crouch jab
which you probably will see yourself getting a lot
it's very hard to confirm the counter hit
but sometimes you actually can- will see it.
I'm pretty good at reacting to it, but it's 'cause I've been playing Street Fighter for so long at this point.
But yeah, you could do crouching jab into crouching medium punch
which is gonna be a pretty damaging, good damage combo from a jab and it'll save you from doing jab light spiral
where you could get a bit more damage from jab
crouch and medium punch, spiral arrow, which is gonna be a pretty good important combo for when you catch your opponent slipping in neutral when they're trying to pressure you and you get a counter hit reversal jab
I would like to call it.
Another important combos is going to be your crouch and fierce counter hit combos
which is crouch fierce counter hit into stand fierce.
And just like the medium punch, if you get it from further range
you can go into the crouching medium kick.
It doesn't work on every range like the stand medium punch
but it will work from further ranges than the stand and fierce.
But if you get it point-blank, always go into that stand fierce.
Very good combo.
Every time.
Okay.
So that is gonna pretty much be all your basic counter hit combos with Cammy.
Now we will move on to the punish counter combos.
And if you don't know what a punish counter combo or a punish counter is
you will get punish counter 100% of the time
even if, let's say, Guile whiffs his button.
Now we're good.
Boom, you always get the punish counter.
You see it show up on the screen.
Obviously further away you won't be able to get a cool punish counter combo
but I just want you to know the basic properties of the punish counter and how you will be landing this.
It's gonna always be from punishing something every time.
And a lot of times you can get
with Cammy, if you whip front or something from a bit closer range
this is- will be your go-to punish counter combo
in my opinion.
You will try to get stand fierce into heavy spin knuckle because this allows you to get a follow-up with a light kick into spiral arrow
which is a very good whip punish combo from further range.
And you need to know that this combo only works on punish counters.
Stand fierce into heavy knuckle, it is only gonna work on punish counter which makes your punish counter and your whip punishing very deadly
I would say, from further back.
The biggest way, of course, for a punish counter is going to be if you block a reversal.
Let me set up Guile to do his reversal.
Anytime you block a reversal, you're going to get a punish counter and this is pretty much gonna be your go-to combo.
This is gonna be your most optimal non-meter combo
which it does require a micro walk.
You cannot just do this combo from crouch fierce back medium punch.
You see, it will whiff every time.
Look at that.
Even if I walk up on a flash kick
look, whiffs every time.
So you do have to put a bit of a walk in there
which is a bit more advanced, of course
but it's gonna be your most optimal combo.
If you don't want to do that, you don't have to
of course.
You can always go with the trustworthy crouch fierce into stand fierce or you can go into
which is another good one, you could go into crouch fierce back medium kick.
..
I meant crouch fierce back heavy kick.
Boom.
And of course, if you a bit late
you could do these combos.
Any regular counter hit combo works as a punish counter combo
so I need, want y'all to know that.
Any combo you learn from me that works on counter hit
it 100% works on the punish counter too.
So boom, look at that.
Every time.
You always wanna punish with that.
This is your best punish.
But of course, this is the most optimal one.
So those are gonna be your pretty much your standard punish counter combos for Cammy.
And now we're gonna get into the drive rush combos
which goes back into the punish counter combos.
Anytime you do a drive rush and is- you do button
it is the same amount of plus frames as the punish counter combo I showed you.
So all of those combos I just showed you will work.
You could go for that.
You can even do this.
Stand fierce, back medium punch, which is gonna pretty much be the most optimal combo you could do.
If you cancel from a low forward, let's say you get the whiff punish with the low forward
you cancel, stand fierce, target combo.
That's gonna be your go-to mid screen.
Now, if you're in a corner, of course you can go into these combos
which is, I wouldn't say they're too advanced.
Honestly, you could, uh, go into crouching fierce
back heavy kick, spiral arrow, DP.
This is gonna be your most optimal ender.
Once you finish and you want to dump all your meter
you will always end with this combo.
Or, if they are standing, after a crouching heavy punch if you do.
..
Let's say you want to dump all your meter into a combo
right?
This is the ender that you want to do
back heavy kick, back heavy kick, spiral arrow
DP.
Or, of course, if you want to dump it you could do back heavy
kick back heavy, kick spiral arrow into level three if you have the bar.
Same thing, that combo does work.
Back heavy kick two times.
Oh my God, I look like a bot.
Boom.
Those are some important drive rush combo.
Another one is going to be off a jab confirm.
Sometimes you might.
..
Can get the kill off of a jab confirm
so you would want to do jab, jab
jab, drive rush into another jab.
So jab, jab, drive rush into another jab is going to be your best friend.
You can also.
..
You can do from that stand jab into stand fierce is probably the best one
honestly.
Pretty simple.
There's really no reason to do another combo from jab
jab.
Just do stand jab into standing fierce.
Spiral arrow is going to be your go-to jab
drive rush combo.
And of course, if you want to meter dump and your opponent is about die
you can do jab, jab, drive rush.
Do the regular jab, drive rush combo
jab fierce into another one, into super.
Also, all these combos work from standing light kick also.
So if you do a jab, uh
drive rush from standing light kick, you can do all of these combos that I just showed you.
They all will work from it.
And of course, if you want to end with level three
the best way to end to level three is always going to be your charge DP into level three.
If you ever do regular DP level three
it will not work.
So, if you want to meter dump all your meter and you're about to kill
you would do that pretty much as your basic ender combo to kill someone.
That's going to be the.
..
Pretty much the simple Cammy combo that you see everyone do to kill
and the more advanced one, of course
is going to be what I showed you earlier.
Which will be your more optimal, and does a bit more in the corner.
Obviously this is a only a corner combo.
And another good drive rush combo I will say that you will want to have in your arsenal is.
..
In the corner you can do combos like this with Cammy if you get a knock-up.
So let's say you get boomed, you can dump some more meter and do a combo like that.
And also, in the corner, it is very important for you to know that no matter how high an opponent.
..
Or, well, not how high, but if you ever land back heavy kick
heavy kick, you can do DP into super.
Not from that height.
See, those heights you will not be able to do it from
but if you let them land a bit lower
this will actually do the most.
And the super will always land in the corner from a charge DP if you land the DP low enough to the opponent.
You will always be able to get charge DP super
but mid screen, do not try this because you can.
..
See here, I do not believe.
Yeah, see, it will never work, but if you see me do this combo in the corner
they will always fall into it after the charge DP.
Remember, even if you're juggling, regular DP level three
boom, never works.
Never regular DP level three.
If you don't want to go for the charge DP level three
you can always just do spiral arrow into a level three
which will be your go-to level three combos
I would say.
Now, for a level one, I would think
say.
..
This is a very important combo, which is going to be your side switch combo here.
This is Cammy's side switch combo.
No meter.
Anytime you land back target combo, you just do heavy hooligan
and it will always side switch if you do target combo.
Anytime you land target combo, you can side switch with this.
Now, if you look here this is a very good way to use level one
I would say.
It's a bit damaging combo.
It's really good, and it's going to.
..
Use up quite a lot of meter, but it's going to get your opponent in the corner and take you out the corner.
It's going to be anytime you land a drive rush
and you can go into crouch fierce, heavy kick
and it will take them all the way to the corner where you are free to start pressuring them.
I would say this combo is very important for Cammy and you're gonna want to learn it.
Anytime you land a drive rush, boom-Here we go.
One more time.
Crouch fears, back heavy kick and then I hold the.
..
You know, you do the drive rush after the back heavy kick.
You do the parry drive rush.
You see me holding the parry?
I want to explain this so people understand the juggle move.
Hold the parry and then just dash.
As you see my input, I start holding very early.
Soon as I do back heavy kick, you can just start holding it and buffering that dash.
So, this gonna be a very important combo for that.
And now for your level two, you have a very important air combo to close out rounds if you do land this
which is going to be- Be quiet.
.
this into heavy DP.
So, anytime you land a charge, uh
target combo, you can go into this level two super.
Be quiet.
So, if you ever land an air to air on someone and you do super immediately
you can get a pretty big- Be quiet.
.
drive rush combo.
Be quiet.
How does he work like that?
Here we go.
You can always get a big drive rush combo.
You can become unique with that right there
just go off that template and you can figure out stuff from there.
So, I would say, pretty much, that is all the basic combos for Cammy
or the basic and the advanced combos, pretty much
from jabs to drive rush to all of that.
Next thing I want to go over is probably going to be Cammy's frame traps
actually.
I think her frame traps is pretty important from the drive rush.
So, this is going to be, like
drive rush frame traps.
So, we're going to show off some drive rush frame traps.
If you do catch your opponent mashing a lot on your plus frames
on drive rush, of course, all these buttons
like I stated earlier, all of these are extremely plus.
So, you can pretty much get some unique frame traps from the drive rush system on block.
As you can see, instead of this medium punch being minus one like it usually is
and if I try to do two, I'm gonna get hit.
But if I do this, here, you see
it always will frame trap their mash.
So, let's say you catch someone mashing
you can do stand medium punch, it will counter hit.
And of course, you know, you just go back to all the counter hit combos I showed earlier and they will work in these situations.
So, let's say you do this, you can frame trap with another one of those.
You could even go for a crouching medium punch and it will trade
and I believe you can get maybe a trade combo from certain ranges if you're close enough.
Yeah, there you go.
So you can get, like, a trade combo with standing light kick.
If you at least go this route, I would recommend just frame trapping with two of those
or you either go for the grab after.
Another big frame trap gonna be from your crouching fears
which is very plus, and you're able to do
of course, the same thing from the standing medium
except crouch medium punch, if you do it this time
it will be real.
So you can do crouch fear, stand medium punch
and this is all going to be part of your pressure.
Get grabbed.
You see here, even though I'm not in range to grab
which I was mashing here, since it's so plus
I can just walk up, grab him and it still will counter hit because I have extreme amounts of plus frames from all of this crouch fears.
Slight step walk forward into grab, boom
it's always going to beat the mash.
And then also, you have your jab frame trap.
Boom.
So if someone tried to mash jab there
you could get a pretty cool trade combo.
Uh, stand fears don't work.
Or he could just go for the grab
of course, which is going to catch the mash every time.
So these are pretty cool, important trade combos that you're going to want to know off of frame trapping with the drive reversal.
So, that's pretty much gonna be how we use Cammy's drive system to get frame traps off.
Also, of course, you have her crouch fears regularly
which is going to frame trap people 'cause it is her only plus button on block
which is crouching fears into stand jab is your best option to go to from crouch fears to frame trap someone
mash and jab.
And the most important one, I think
is the crouch jab chains.
If you do chain your crouch jab and someone mash
they will get hit every time.
So this is.
..
And a very important frame trap.
Since crouch jabs are minus on block, people like to mash a lot.
But since they're chainable, they become a real frame trap.
But if you do wait one second late
boom, you're going to get hit every time.
You see that?
I'm trying to.
..
Wait a second, you just chain them and it will beat the mash every time.
So that is pretty much going to be how you want to pressure with Cammy and frame trap people to open them up and
uh, just create advantageous situations for yourself on offense.
The next thing we're going to go over is going to be meteys for Cammy.
If you don't know what a meaty is
it's pretty much going to be something else that stops your opponent from doing wake up buttons
as we can show right now when I knock Guile down.
He on a wake up button.
And now, if you mess this timing up
let's say you just timing it off of steel
boom, you can just get hit and mashed on-So
since you don't want to mess this up
you want to kind of find set-ups that just time themselves and you don't even have to think about it
manually timing your grab or your button or whatever it is
so you don't actually get mashed on.
The one of the most important ones for Cammy that I've found
obviously this is things that I've found, I don't.
..
I will say there's going to be a lot more
maybe better than these in the future, but these ones are the ones that I have right now and that I use in my matches that I play.
Which is going to be.
..
After heavy drill, no matter where you get heavy drill
dash crouch fears mid-screen every time is going to be extremely meaty
and as you seen, it beat the wake-up button.
Every time it's going to win.
And let's say, even if your opponent hold up and you don't get that counter hit
you can always, on this meaty, go into stand fears.
Let me take them off so there's no counter hit.
So when you land this meaty, it is so meaty that you can combo and to stand fears always.
Look at that.
Every time, this is auto-timed, you don't have to think about it.
You dash forward.
You do spiral arrow, heavy spiral arrow
dash forward, crouch fears.
It's going to meaty every time, a very good mid-screen.
And you could dash.
If you have to time your throw, you just kind of have to time it manually
which you just kind of dash and wait a slight second and then you just go for throw
which should be pretty easy.
But if you do want to strike every time
this is going to be your go-to meaty here.
On block it is very plus also.
It's not going to be plus one like the usual crouch fears.
This one is actually going to be.
..
This one is plus three.
So as you can see, this is plus three
so you could get more unique with the frame traps if you want to.
You could do like a stand medium punch in between.
If they mash and jab, walk up though.
So this is going to be a lot more plus
where you can create more unique frame traps instead of this typical stand jab after the crouch fears that we've been showing
the stand jab to stop them from mashing
you could do different button combinations depending on the start-up frames
of course, of the button.
So that's going to be pretty much your main meaty
I would say, after spiral arrow, and that's what I see myself doing mid-screen pretty much most of the time.
You're going to pretty much be doing that mid-screen anytime you're doing a combo in their mid-screen from heavy spiral arrow
you're going to see yourself doing that meaty.
Now in the corner, this is what I would say is the most important meaty that you need to know as a Cammy player
is after your grab, it stops people from holding up
mash and jab, everything, is going to be slight step forward
stand medium punch.
Now as you know, you can never do this combo right as a regular combo with stand medium
but after the grab, this stand medium punch hits so meaty
you can always combo into the crouching medium punch.
This is going to be your most important meaty as a Cammy player after grab
'cause you're going to see yourself landing a lot of grabs in the corner.
You going to need to know this meaty extremely well.
And you have to time it, though.
It is not auto-timed, this is a manually timed meaty
so you actually have to just do it yourself and get the rhythm and timing down of people hold up a lot
you don't get a counter hit.
Boom, it's going to catch the hold up
and you're going to actually meaty them so they cannot jump out.
And another good thing is that now this damn medium punch becomes plus one on block
it is no longer negative like we see it usually.
Sometimes you will get a zero, but it will never be negative on block no matter what.
So that means it's never not your turn to pressure again.
You can always go for a jab.
You could always go for a jab or a light kick into a combo.
So this is going to be your most important meaty after throw.
The only bad downside to meaties I will tell you in this game before we get into the next one is perfect parry.
If your opponent does wake up, let's say we set him to wake up parry
'cause I don't want y'all to think that it's just amazing to go for the meaty every time.
If we set him to wake up parry
he's going to get a perfect parry pretty much every single time.
So of course, it is a mind game where if they perfect parry
you get to punish counter throw and it does extra damage.
So there is a downside to doing these perfect meaties that hit on frame one pretty much on wake up.
They can be perfect parries, so I want y'all to remember that when you're playing your opponent.
Maybe they might try to do that and throw that out.
It will hit you every time and they are pretty much guaranteed a combo
but do not let it stop you from doing your meaties because it is very important to do these.
Uh, yeah, I guess general strategies is- will be the last category that we go over.
And pretty much when I'm playing Cammy, a lot of times.
..
And she is very good versus fireballs.
Obviously you have the Hooligan, so very anti-fireball move.
When you're fighting a fireball character, you always want to keep in mind that Hooligan and EX Hooligan is a bit faster
so maybe if you have a bit slower reaction
you can try out the EX Hooligan.
That is obviously the general game plan when you're fighting.
A lot of the fireball characters is to make them stop shooting fireballs early on with the Hooligan.
And then they are forced to play your game as Cammy
which is playing neutral, getting whip punishes with your buttons
which is always what I'm looking for.
A lot of times when I'm playing, I'm looking for a whip punish with low forward into spiral arrow or into my drive rush combo
of course, that we went over earlier.
So a lot of times I'm just looking to catch that one whip punish here
start my offense, and then Cammy becomes very deadly in the corner because it starts your offense up.
Another thing with Cammy, when I'm pressuring people
a lot of times, especially in the corner
I'm always looking to space my divekicks out so that I'm extremely plus and I can keep my turn on offense.
This is very good in the corner I would say
especially, because it is very easy to just space out your divekicks and it's very hard for your opponent to anti-air their divekicks.
So they're always very good to do to keep pressure on.
And it just make your opponent feel very unusual on when they want to press that button.
Also, it takes down drive gauge, right?
So every divekick you do is going to take down a little bit of drive gauge.
You can do this mid-screen, of course.
Going to be a little bit harder since your opponent can walk back and forth.
And then you want to start, of course
mixing in some regular jumps.
You don't want to only do divekicks because then it becomes a bit too predictable and easy to anti-air
but when you start mixing in the regular jumps with the divekicks
it gets a lot harder to anti-air Cammy.
Of course, you don't want to just jump around a lot
you have to mix in a lot of good neutral whip punishes
making them scared on the ground.
And then of course you want to start approaching from the air a bit
but this is just how, you know
Cammy's game plan is, of course.
So a lot of times just looking for whip punishes.
And then, you know, of course you have your trustworthy throw loop in the corner.
This is going to be a big part of Cammy's game plan and it goes back into the meaty I showed you.
This is why that makes the meaty really good because your opponent will probably start trying to press buttons or jump out the corner or backdash
because if they do backdash, a lot of people do that now because it does put them in an advantageous situation as you can see.
But since when you do time their throw loop correctly as a meaty throw
so you're only minus two, as in if you had to time it regularly and you mess it up
you might mess it up, and then you become minus nine where they can actually punish you
which is why Cammy throw loop is good.
You just take a few slight step forward and then throw.
It's very easy to get the timing down and that way you will be safe from these backdashes
which people will start doing.
But that's why you do this meaty here
and look at that, it catches the backdash
you get a combo you wouldn't usually get
and it's a lot more damage.
If you want to cash out, you see
this why this meaty is probably the most important one because it is a part of your very
very, very important strategy as a Cammy player
I would say.
So yes, people will try to backdash out your pressure because they know in this game
throws have a lot of recovery, so you can actually backdash punish if people mistime their grab.
Or let's say they even walked out of your pressure and you just like mistimed your grab there because they just walked back
sometimes that does happen.
They get a lot of good punishes mid-screen
but this is pretty much probably going to be your general game plan with Cammy.
And I would say honestly also when you put people in the corner
a lot of times I like to.
..
Instead of anti-airing with DP, I will go for a jump medium punch and an EX divekick.
I think this is important in your strategy actually for the simple fact that this is going to do a lot of damage and it's going to make people not want to try to jump out the corner.
'Cause you can do combos like this, you know
that just does so much damage and even if you don't want to spend all the drive gauge after
you can always just end it with DP of course
but you can do sand fears into spiral arrow DP.
Look at that.
You just gotta do the drive rush period that I showed you earlier
hold the button down, and you can get big combos from the air-to-air.
So I would say keep that in mind.
You can obviously do this mid-screen too, but people love to jump out the corner and you just get really cool combos.
Even mid-screen you could do a combo like that if you have a level three from it.
So this honestly, if you can anti-air with it every time
it'll be your go-to anti-air, but obviously air-to-air and sometimes it's not as natural as doing a DP or maybe your back medium punch.
I think that's pretty much going to be the finish of the tutorial.
I think we covered pretty much everything that can help you come to the next level with Cammy.
I'm going to pretty much be trying to do this for a lot of the characters in Street Fighter 6
so let me know down in the comment section below which.
..
Who you would like to see next and let me know how you felt about this tutorial overall.
This is my first one ever, so it might not be extremely perfect
but I tried to make it the best that I could so that everyone can understand the character and obviously level up and reach a level that maybe you thought you wouldn't reach so fast.
I just hope that it can help everyone.
So let me know down below if it did help you and what character you would like to see next.
And of course, make sure you leave a like on the video
subscribe to the channel, and as always
I'll see you in the next one.